Will Mills







Summary / Skills

I'm a Software Engineer based in Toronto, Canada. I'm the co-creator of RedPoint, a web native computational notebook. I have multiple years of experience in both the Ruby and JavaScript ecosystems, and am comfortable with GCP and Docker.

Frontend	Backend	Tooling
JavaScript (ES6+), React/Redux,	Ruby, Rails, Node.is, SOL.	Git/Github, Docker, Linux,
Ember.js, HTML/CSS, jQuery	MongoDB, Redis, Sinatra	WebSockets, RSpec, Agile,
		JIRA, GCP, DigitalOcean

Professional Experience

2020 - Present **Software Developer**, Financelt

- Automated processes to increase operational efficiency saving approximately 2000 hours of manual work per year
- Launched third party integration for online identity verification service to securely handle fintrac requirements
- Redesigned and updated internal QA tools to increase effectiveness and joy in using them
- Implemented internal services to auto-block or unblock loans from funding under various triggering scenarios
- Refactored and updated dynamically generated legal documents to comply with regional financial regulations

2019 - 2020 **Co-Creator, Software Engineer**, RedPoint Notebooks

- Co-created a web-native computational notebook designed for sharing and presenting live programming notes
- Architected and implemented back-end server architecture using Node.js, Express, Docker, Redis
- Designed delimiter system to drastically improve performance of processing cell-based code for slotting output
- Created a client-server architecture model that uses Websockets for full duplex client-server communication
- Designed and built front end using responsive mobile-first principles in React.js
- Created a language collation system and a server-side queue to execute multiple languages with one click

2018 - 2019 Full-Stack Web Developer, Self-Employed

Developed various web applications for personal and OSS projects using Rails, React/Redux, SQL

EDUCATION

2005 - 2009 **B.A. Sociology**, Ryerson University, Toronto